Guide to the David Rakoff Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Rakoff papers
1949-2012
GEN MSS 1015
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
13.34
(17 boxes)
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, datebooks, notebooks, financial papers, photographs, artwork, rubber stamps, printed materials, audiovisual materials, and other papers by, to, or relating to David Rakoff. Writings include multiple drafts of Rakoff's essay collections Fraud, Don't Get Too Comfortable, and Half Empty.
Rakoff, David, 1964-2012
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David Rakoff on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 16 (film reels): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 17 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
David Rakoff (1964-2012)
David Rakoff was a Canadian writer based in New York City known for humorous non-fiction essays and as a contributor to the radio program This American Life.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, datebooks, notebooks, financial papers, photographs, artwork, rubber stamps, printed materials, audiovisual materials, and other papers by, to, or relating to David Rakoff. Writings include multiple drafts of Rakoff's essay collections Fraud, Don't Get Too Comfortable, and Half Empty.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Correspondence, 1949-2012. II. Writings, 1990s-2000s. III. Personal Papers, 1980s-2010s. IV. Printed Materials, 1990s-2008. V. Audiovisual Materials, 1980s. VI. Electronic Media, 2000s.
Authors, Canadian -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, Canadian -- 21st century -- Archives; Essayists, Canadian -- 20th Century -- Archives; Essayists, Canadian -- 21st century -- Archives; Gay authors; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Photographs; Rakoff, David, 1964-2012
- Correspondence, 1949-2012; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically. Materials previously intermixed with correspondence are grouped together following the correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982; 2 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1983; 2 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984; 2 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985; 4 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986; 2 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988; 3 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989; 3 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990; 2 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1993; 3 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1995; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1998; 3 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2000; 2 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2001; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2002; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2003; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2004; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2005; 3 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2006; 3 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2007; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2009; 3 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, undated; 20 (Box 4)
  - Material previously intermixed with correspondence, 1949-2010s
    - Artwork - small painting and sketch, circa 2001 (Box 5)
    - The Boston Star, 1995 Summer (Box 5)
      Scope and Contents
      Material was tightly folded into a long U-shape.
    - Home-made books (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous newspapers and clippings (Box 5)
    - The New Yorker, 1995 (Box 5)
    - The New York Times - various, 2 (Box 5)
    - Paper napkin - "Marry me please" (Box 5)
    - Personal and financial papers (Box 5)
    - Photographs, 2 (Box 5)
    - Playbill - A Streetcar Named Desire, 1949 October 31 (Box 5)
    - Playbills, 1950s-2008; 17 (Box 5)
    - Programs and event announcements, 5 (Box 6)
    - Small sewing kit and penny (Box 6)
    - Thank-you notes (Box 6)
      Mostly from young students.
    - The Village Voice, 1995 January 31 (Box 6)
    - Writings by David Rakoff and others, 2 (Box 6)
- Writings, 1990s-2000s; Series II
  Writings include typescripts, corrected proofs, and galleys for works including Fraud, Don't Get Too Comfortable, and Half Empty. See also Series I. Correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by file title.
  - Articles and reviews, published, 2 (Box 6)
  - Articles and reviews - typescripts, some with edits (Box 6)
  - Chanel / Haute couture (Box 6)
  - "David Rakoff - New Script" - 3 clean typescript copies, removed from binder, with blank application to Actors' Equity Association, 2 (Box 6)
  - Don't Get Too Comfortable - second draft, corrected, with comments by Kendra Harpoter (Doubleday), 2004 (Box 6)
  - Don't Get Too Comfortable - typescripts with notes, commentary and letter by Bill Thomas (Doubleday), 2 (Box 6)
  - eine DATA base - NAM JUNE PAIK - edition cantz, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Fraud: Essays - commentary and corrections from Pamela Murray, 2000 September 25 (Box 6)
  - Fraud: Essays - handwritten comments (Box 6)
  - Fraud: Essays - miscellaneous TS pages with corrections (Box 6)
  - Fraud: Essays - typescript, first draft with edits and artwork, 2 (Box 6)
  - Fraud - "Re-draft" - clean typescript with artwork, 2000 October; 2 (Box 7)
  - Fraud - "Re-draft" - typescript with edits, 2000 October; 2 (Box 7)
  - Half Empty - bound galleys, 2010; 2 (Box 7)
  - Half Empty - typescript with edits and commentary by Bill Thomas (Doubleday), 2010; 2 (Box 7)
  - Little Freida Mysteries - typescript with highlighting, and rehearsal schedule (Box 7)
  - The Little Freida Mysteries - typescript with notes and highlighting (Box 7)
  - "March Drama Department Play" - rough draft and untitled script, removed from binder with clipping (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous drafts, transcripts, etc. (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous script pages - typescript with edits and highlighting (Box 7)
  - Pages from a script with highlighting and edits, removed from binder (Box 7)
  - Script with edits, photocopied (Box 7)
  - "World of Damages" [?], 2 (Box 7)
- Personal papers, 1980s-2010s; Series III
  Personal appers include diaries and day planners, financial papers, photographs and slides, artwork, and rubber stamps. See also Series I. Correspondence.
  Diaraies are arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries and Day planners, 1988-2009
    - Day planner, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Diary, 1991 March -November (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1994 (Box 7)
    - Day planner, 1995 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Blank notebook with journal entries, sketches, miscellaneous inserts, 1996 November - December (Box 8)
    - Desk diary, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2002 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2003 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2004 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2006 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2007 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2008 (Box 8)
    - Day planner, 2009 (Box 8)
    - Diary, 1998 August - 1999 May (Box 8)
    - Diary, 1999 April - October (Box 8)
    - Diary, 1999 November /December - 2000 May (Box 8)
    - Diary, 2000 June-2001 January (Box 8)
    - Diary, 2001 February - 2002 March (Box 9)
    - Diary, 2002 May 9 and June 24 - 2003 January (Box 9)
    - Diary, 2003 February - 2006 December (Box 9)
    - Diary, 2007 January (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook - "Tokyo, Iceland, Aspen, Loch Ness...", 1999 April (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook, 2002 August - 2003 October (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook - "Maybe", circa 2003 - 2006 (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook - "Because", circa 2004 (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook, circa 2004 - 2006 (Box 9)
    - Personal notebook - "New [...] SAD", circa 2007 (Box 9)
  - Financial papers
    - Don't Get Too Comfortable - publication agreement (Box 9)
    - Fraud - Financial papers and related correspondence (Box 9)
  - Photographs and slides
    - Photographs, 7 (Box 9)
    - Photographs, 10 (Box 10)
    - Photonegatives and trimmings (Box 10)
    - Slides, 2 (Box 10)
    - "Backstage Press" tag and receipts - [Removed from photographs] (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and ephemera related to photographs (Box 10)
  - Artwork
    - "Basic Books" graphics (Box 10)
    - "Green/Renzi" graphics (Box 10)
    - Half Empty artwork (Box 10)
    - Herter Studios and other graphics (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous graphics (Box 10)
    - Modern Times graphics and cutouts (Box 10)
  - Rubber stamps
    - Patterns for rubber stamps (Box 10)
    - Ribbon (Box 11)
      Originally tied around the rubber stamps.
    - Hand-carved rubber stamps, 3 (Box 11)
    - Hand-carved rubber stamps, 3 (Box 12)
    - Hand-carved rubber stamps - Basic Books (Box 13)
    - Hand-carved rubber stamps - Harter studio, 2 (Box 13)
    - Stationery (Box 10)
- Printed materials, 1990s - 2008; Series IV
  Printed materials include various New York periodicals and clippings of theatre reviews. See also Series I. Correspondence.
  - The New York Times Magazine, 2001 September 23 (Box 10)
  - The New York Times and Observatory, 1996-1997 (Box 10)
  - The New Yorker, 2001 September 24 and 2008 November 17 (Box 10)
  - Press reviews of theater productions, 1990s; 2 (Box 10)
  - The New York Times, 2008 November 5 (Box 14)
  - Daily News, 2001 September 12 (Box 14)
  - New York Post, 2001 September 12 (Box 14)
  - The New York Times - two copies, 2001 September 12 (Box 14)
  - The New York Times Book Review- Paperback Best Sellers - Framed, 2006 October 29 (Box 15)
- Audiovisual materials, 1980s; Series V
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - "Pain D'Amour", David Rakoff / Tosh Ozawa - film reels, 1980s; (2 film reels) (Box 16)
- Electronic media, 2000s; Series V; 4 (Box 17)
  Includes CDs, DVDs and an external hard drive.
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.